All right.
So the first thing we need to do here is to create two new files.
So let's expand the project folder.
And at the main folder, right click and go to new source file.
And call it rugby underscore led see.
And choose default.
See Source.
And now create a head of file.
And call it rugby underscore led and choose default.
See header template.
OC.
Next, we need to update the C list file and add the GB led source file so be sure that it's the C list
file here on the main.
And add g B underscore led C and save it.
So now let's head over to the header file.
So here in the header file, we'll define the rugby led GPO as the number of rugby channels, the configuration
structure and the prototypes for the color statuses.
So let's start by defining the rugby led GPOs.
And we'll say define.
GP led read GPIO and will use IO 21.
Now define the rugby led green GPIO.
As I oh 22.
So now let's define the blue one.
And we can use 23.
So now here we can define the number of channels.
So we'll say rugby led colour mix channels.
And we'll say define.
G b led channel num.
And we'll have three, right for red, green and blue.
So now let's define the configuration structure.
We'll say ruby led configuration.
And we'll make it a typedef struct.
And we'll have here a channel.
It GPIO and INT mode.
And timer index.
So now let's call it ldl-c info underscore RT.
Now copy this and we can create an array with the same length as the number of channels.
We could do that using our GP led channel num.
Okay, great.
So now we need the prototypes for the color statuses.
So the first one we can do is the color to indicate that the wi fi application has started.
So let's just make a comment here colored to indicate.
WI fi application started.
And let's say void RG be led wi fi app started and it takes no input parameters.
Okay, So the next one will be the color to indicate that the HTTP server has started.
And we'll say void our Gbps led http server started.
And this is void as well.
In the last one is the color to indicate that the ESP 32 is connected to an access point.
And this will be void.
RG be led wi fi connected and it's void as well.
All right, so that's it.
So now we can move on to the implementation and the GB LMDC file.
Okay.
So first let's include std bool.
And then also include the driver for DCH.
And this is for legacy driver.
And also include the rugby LED header file here as well.
So first we need to create a function that initializes the rugby led settings per channel.
Including the GPIO for each color.
The mode and the time of configuration.
So this is going to be a static function, meaning it's restricted to this file and it returns void.
Call it rg be led p w m in it and it's void.
And then I'll here define a variable that we'll use to iterate through the rugby channels and that can
be an int, call it rugby underscore.
And at this point we can configure the rugby channel structures.
Let's do the read first here.
So it's C underscore, c.
H.
Which is the array that we created in the header file.
So at the first position, update the channel.
And from the LDCs.
DRIVER We'll use Channel Zero.
All right.
So choose Channel Zero.
And let's copy this.
Update the GPIO as RG be led, read GPIO and set the mode.
Here is high speed mode.
And the timer.
Is going to be time or zero.
All right, So choose a time or zero.
We can now take care of the Green Channel.
So for the Green Channel, this is going to be Channel one.
So update all the members to channel one.
And that'll be EDC Channel one.
And the GPIO should be green.
So next, let's update the blue channel.
And this is the same story here.
So update the channel for each structure member.
The channel number as well should be channeled to.
The GPIO is blue.
And at this point here we can configure the timer.
So configure timer zero.
And will specify the timer config struct.
From the LMDC driver.
All right.
And call it EDC underscore timer.
And we'll update the first member duty resolution.
As la EDC timer.
Eight bits.
And then now the frequency member here, 100 hertz should be fast enough.
And for the speed mode.
Use led DC high speed mode.
And the time a number.
Will be led DC Timer zero.
All right, so that's all for the timer.
And now we can call EDC timer config.
This one here and then pass a reference to the structure.
All right.
So lastly, let's configure the channels based on the rugby channel settings that we've just done.
So we'll grab this variable here and we're going to use it to increment through the channels.
So here we'll say configure channels.
And say for the FF variable equals zero.
Four rugby channels less than the total number of channels.
We're going to increment through the channels.
And here we need to update the EDC channel config struct from the driver.
And call it channel.
And we're going to update the channel member.
Using that increment variable.
Like so.
And for the duty, we can leave it as zero.
And for the H point member, we can make that zero as well.
And next, we can update the GPIO number using our settings and the increment variable.
And the interrupt type should be disabled, which we can take from the driver.
Interrupt, disable.
OC and for the speed mode, we could take that from our settings as well.
Using the rugby channel variable.
Also four timers select.
This can be updated using our settings above.
From the timer index.
Okay, great.
So now we can call the DC channel config function.
And then pass a reference to the struct.
This will be done for each iteration through the loop and next takes care of our p w m GB channels initialization.
So next we'll take care of the set colour function.
So let's make a comment here.
Sets the rugby colour.
All right, So here's, say, static void.
Rugby led set colour and that's a UNT eight type for the red and also for the green and blue channels
as well.
So here we specified the input type as you went eight because we've specified the duty resolution is
eight bits.
Therefore the duty cycle values can range from 0 to 255.
All right.
So let's make a comment here.
Value should be.
0 to 255 for an eight bit number.
And we'll use the D.C. set duty function.
From the driver and for the speed passer, see Channel Zero.
For the speed mode and the EDC Channel Zero.
As the channel.
And this is the Red Channel.
OC so now call DC.
Update duty from the driver.
And for the speed, it's again see Channel Zero.
And let's see.
Channel zero for the channel as well.
Okay.
So just copy these two lines and we can take care of Channel one as well and just update the color parameter
as green and then the channel as one.
So now do the same for the blue channel.
Change this to channel two.
And now this is for blue.
Okay, so that's our GB set color function.
Now let's create the status colors that we'll use in the application.
So go to the head of file.
And copy these prototypes.
And then paste them into the C file.
Let's get rid of these comments as they're already in the header file so we don't need them here.
So for wi fi started we'll call our GB led p w init function.
And then we'll set the color.
I mentioned in the intro video, and that is 250 5102 and 255.
That's the magenta type color that I showed in the intro.
And this function, we only need to call it once.
So we need a global variable to indicate whether it's already been initialized.
So we'll say handle for RGV.
Led P.W. and in it.
And say bull and call it g, underscore p w and it handle and initialize it to false.
And let's use this here and set it to true before the function is completed.
All right.
And then let's come back here.
And check if it hasn't been initialized.
And if it hasn't?
Then we'll go ahead and initialize by calling the function.
So copied the same and do this for the http server started.
And then update the color as you like.
I'll use the yellowish color that I had shown previously.
Again.
Set your wi fi connected color.
I'll use the blueish greenish colors I had previously shown.
All right.
Yes.
So that's it.
You could probably define some macros for these color values when you know what you want, just so you're
not using these magic numbers as we're doing here.
So for now, let's test these out in the main file.
And to do that, we'll need to include the GP led file.
And just put the status function here.
Say rg be led wi fi up started.
And change the delay to 1000 milliseconds.
And then now we can put in the GP led HTTP server started.
And then add another delay.
And then we also want to test the rugby led wi fi connected function.
And we can include another delay here.
So the color should change at this interval.
So now go ahead and build the project.
And just give it a minute.
So once the build is complete, let's go flash the dev kit.
And I've plugged mine into a different port, but that's not a problem.
I can update it easily by coming up here and then changing the port from my rover kit.
And then we can just hit flash again.
All right, so now let's check out the rugby led.
Cool.
So we have the wi fi up started, web server started and wi fi connected status is all shining, so
our status LEDs are good to go in the next section.
Let's get wi fi up and running.
So I'll see you there.